The world's most dangerous times created the world's most dangerous group.
Straight Outta Compton is a drama, music, history film directed by F. Gary Gray.
In 1987, five young men, using brutally honest rhymes and hardcore beats, put their frustration and anger about
life in the most dangerous place in America into the most powerful weapon they had: their music.
Taking us back to where it all began, Straight Outta Compton tells the true story of how these cultural rebels—armed only with their lyrics, swagger,
bravado and raw talent—stood up to the authorities that meant to keep them down and formed the world’s most dangerous group, N.W.A.
And as they spoke the truth that no one had before and exposed life in the hood, their
voice ignited a social revolution that is still reverberating today.
Ice Cube, played by O'Shea Jackson Jr..
Dr. Dre, played by Corey Hawkins.
Eazy-E, played by Jason Mitchell.
DJ Yella, played by Neil Brown Jr..
MC Ren, played by Aldis Hodge.
Jerry Heller, played by Paul Giamatti.
Straight Outta Compton is a 2015 American epic biographical drama film that tells the
story of hip-hop group N.W.A's rise and fall under manager Jerry Heller.
The film, directed by F.
Gary Gray, stars O’Shea Jackson Jr., Corey Hawkins,
and Jason Mitchell as Ice Cube, Dr.
Dre, and Eazy-E, respectively.
Released in August 2015, the film received critical acclaim and was a
box office success, grossing $201.6 million worldwide.
Straight Outta Compton earned several awards and nominations, including an Academy Award nomination for Best
Original Screenplay and a win for Outstanding Motion Picture at the 47th NAACP Image Awards.
The film explores themes of drug dealer, police brutality,
husband wife relationship, rap music, hip-hop.
The tone is dark and emotional.